<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Penghao Xu</title>
    <link>http://penghao.best/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://penghao.best/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:39:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://penghao.best/media/sharing.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>http://penghao.best/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human mtDNA paper accepted by NAR</title>
      <link>http://penghao.best/post/20231205_human_mt_accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 23:39:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://penghao.best/post/20231205_human_mt_accepted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our new paper, titled &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Light-strand bias and enriched zones of embedded ribonucleotides are associated with DNA replication and transcription in the human-mitochondrial genome&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; is accepted in &lt;em&gt;Nucleic Acids Research&lt;/em&gt;. In this paper, we revealed the rNMP incorporation characteristics, and its relation to replication and protein coding genes in human mtDNA. We hope this paper can help us to uncover some functionality of the abundant rNMP incorporation in DNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Francesca Storici&lt;/strong&gt; for all the guidance and support in this study. Thanks my co-first author, &lt;strong&gt;Taehwan Yang&lt;/strong&gt; for his tremendous effort and input to this paper. Thanks all the authors for your help and contribution: Kundnani, Deepali; Sun, Mo; Marsili, Stefania; Gombolay, Alli; Jeon, Youngkyu; Newnam, Gary; Balachander, Sathya; Bazzani, Veronica; Baccarani, Umberto; Park, Vivian; Tao, Sijia; Lori, Adriana; Schinazi, Raymond; Kim, Baek; Pursell, Zachary; Tell, Gianluca; Vascotto, Carlo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the full abstract of this paper. I&amp;rsquo;m always willing to talk if you have any questions or ideas about our study!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abundant ribonucleoside-triphosphate (rNTP) incorporation into DNA by DNA polymerases in the form of ribonucleoside monophosphates (rNMPs) is a widespread phenomenon in nature, resulting in DNA-structural change and genome instability. The rNMP distribution, characteristics, hotspots, and association with DNA metabolic processes in human mitochondrial DNA (hmtDNA) remain mostly unknown. Here, we utilize the ribose-seq technique to capture embedded rNMPs in hmtDNA of six different cell types. In most cell types, the rNMPs are preferentially embedded on the light strand of hmtDNA with a strong bias towards rCMPs; while in the liver-tissue cells, the rNMPs are predominately found on the heavy strand. We uncover common rNMP hotspots and conserved rNMP-enriched zones across the entire hmtDNA, including in the control region, which links the rNMP presence to the frequent hmtDNA replication-failure events. We show a strong correlation between coding-sequence size and rNMP-embedment frequency per nucleotide on the non-template, light strand in all cell types, supporting the presence of transient RNA-DNA hybrids preceding light-strand replication. Moreover, we detect rNMP-embedment patterns that are only partly conserved across the different cell types and are distinct from those found in yeast mtDNA. The study opens new research directions to understand the biology of hmtDNA and genomic rNMPs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Science Fund scholarship</title>
      <link>http://penghao.best/post/20230131_x1_fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 23:39:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://penghao.best/post/20230131_x1_fellowship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am glad to announce that I was awarded the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keystonesymposia.org/financial-aid/scholarships&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Keystone Symposia Future of Science Fund scholarship&lt;/a&gt; from the conference &lt;strong&gt;Keystone Symposia X1: Genomic Instability and DNA repair&lt;/strong&gt;. At the upcoming conference, I will be presenting new findings on the characteristics of rNMP incorporation in human mtDNA. Welcome to view my poster (and attend my potential talk) in Whistler, BC, Canada on Mar 19-23! Please feel free to stop by and discuss my research with me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduation!</title>
      <link>http://penghao.best/post/20230210_graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 23:39:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://penghao.best/post/20230210_graduation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is with great pride and appreciation that I announce the completion of my Ph.D. in Bioinformatics at Georgia Tech, with a thesis entitled &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Revealing patterns of ribonucleotide incorporation in genomic DNA of eukaryotic cells&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. Throughout my five-year journey, I was fortunate enough to receive invaluable guidance from my advisor, &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Francesca Storici&lt;/strong&gt;, and unwavering support from my committee members: &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Mark Borodovsky&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Shamkant Navathe&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Patrick McGrath&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Fredrik Vannberg&lt;/strong&gt;. I am excited to continue my research in Storici Lab as a postdoc, with a particular focus on investigating rNMP incorporation in DNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/20230210_graduation/diploma_hu73de0e0ebcff53e7ff54438531ac0c21_244237_e094908c5e6dc5c592d56218519b282e.webp 400w,
               /post/20230210_graduation/diploma_hu73de0e0ebcff53e7ff54438531ac0c21_244237_c9bf4f687b1d8dcc5d000a51594ab669.webp 760w,
               /post/20230210_graduation/diploma_hu73de0e0ebcff53e7ff54438531ac0c21_244237_1200x1200_fit_q99_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://penghao.best/post/20230210_graduation/diploma_hu73de0e0ebcff53e7ff54438531ac0c21_244237_e094908c5e6dc5c592d56218519b282e.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;615&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got a Congratulation letter from U.S. Senator &lt;strong&gt;Jon Ossoff&lt;/strong&gt; !!! &amp;#x1f606;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/20230210_graduation/jon_hu6f44e4e59cb1b8b94fb3002abd462f70_73802_d0eeabad121b79f7558f94c8b2d2cb88.webp 400w,
               /post/20230210_graduation/jon_hu6f44e4e59cb1b8b94fb3002abd462f70_73802_0311889ced99f5544199d33bcbeb4993.webp 760w,
               /post/20230210_graduation/jon_hu6f44e4e59cb1b8b94fb3002abd462f70_73802_1200x1200_fit_q99_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://penghao.best/post/20230210_graduation/jon_hu6f44e4e59cb1b8b94fb3002abd462f70_73802_d0eeabad121b79f7558f94c8b2d2cb88.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;471&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
